<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="hyprland_toplevel_export_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2022 Vaxry

    Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
    modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met:

    1. Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice,
       this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.

    2. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice,
       this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation
       and/or other materials provided with the distribution.

    3. Neither the name of the copyright holder nor the names of its contributors
       may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software
       without specific prior written permission.

    THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS"
    AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE
    IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE
    DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDER OR CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE
    FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL
    DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR
    SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER
    CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY,
    OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE
    OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="hyprland_toplevel_export_manager_v1" version="2">
    <description summary="manager to begin capturing">
      This object advertises requests to start capturing the contents of another
      client's toplevel surface. Each capture request creates a new frame object
      that advertises the supported buffer types and eventually delivers the
      captured pixels.
    </description>

    <request name="capture_toplevel">
      <description summary="capture a toplevel by handle">
        Capture the next frame of a toplevel identified by its Hyprland handle.
        The frame will contain all subsurfaces and popups belonging to the
        toplevel. If overlay_cursor is non-zero the server is allowed to include
        the current cursor image in the capture.
      </description>
      <arg name="frame" type="new_id" interface="hyprland_toplevel_export_frame_v1"/>
      <arg name="overlay_cursor" type="int"/>
      <arg name="handle" type="uint"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the manager">
        Destroys the manager. All frames that have not been destroyed yet remain
        valid, but no new capture requests may be issued afterwards.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="capture_toplevel_with_wlr_toplevel_handle" since="2">
      <description summary="capture a toplevel using a wlr_foreign handle">
        Same as capture_toplevel but the toplevel is identified by a
        zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1 instead of a Hyprland-specific numeric
        handle.
      </description>
      <arg name="frame" type="new_id" interface="hyprland_toplevel_export_frame_v1"/>
      <arg name="overlay_cursor" type="int"/>
      <arg name="handle" type="object" interface="zwlr_foreign_toplevel_handle_v1"/>
    </request>
  </interface>

  <interface name="hyprland_toplevel_export_frame_v1" version="2">
    <description summary="a frame ready for copying">
      Represents a single capture operation. After creation the compositor will
      enumerate the supported buffer types (wl_shm and/or linux-dmabuf) and
      eventually send either a ready or failed event. Once one of those events
      fires the client should destroy the frame.
    </description>

    <event name="buffer">
      <description summary="wl_shm buffer description">
        Announces a wl_shm buffer layout that can be used to copy this frame.
      </description>
      <arg name="format" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="width" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="height" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="stride" type="uint"/>
    </event>

    <event name="damage">
      <description summary="damaged region">
        Announces a box that changed since the previous ready event. Multiple
        damage events may be emitted for the same frame.
      </description>
      <arg name="x" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="y" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="width" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="height" type="uint"/>
    </event>

    <event name="flags">
      <description summary="frame flags">
        Announces flags that describe the capture. Sent once before ready.
      </description>
      <arg name="flags" type="uint"/>
    </event>

    <event name="ready">
      <description summary="frame is ready for reading">
        Sent when the compositor has finished copying the frame into the
        provided buffer. Includes a presentation timestamp.
      </description>
      <arg name="tv_sec_hi" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="tv_sec_lo" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="tv_nsec" type="uint"/>
    </event>

    <event name="failed">
      <description summary="frame capture failed">
        Indicates that copying the frame failed. After receiving this event the
        client should destroy the frame object.
      </description>
    </event>

    <event name="linux_dmabuf">
      <description summary="linux-dmabuf buffer description">
        Announces parameters for capturing into a linux-dmabuf buffer.
      </description>
      <arg name="format" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="width" type="uint"/>
      <arg name="height" type="uint"/>
    </event>

    <event name="buffer_done">
      <description summary="all buffer types reported">
        Sent after all buffer events for this frame have been emitted. The
        client can now choose one of the advertised buffer types and issue the
        copy request.
      </description>
    </event>

    <request name="copy">
      <description summary="copy the frame into a wl_buffer">
        Copies the frame into the supplied buffer. The buffer must match one of
        the formats described by prior buffer events. If ignore_damage is set
        the compositor may copy without waiting for additional damage.
      </description>
      <arg name="buffer" type="object" interface="wl_buffer"/>
      <arg name="ignore_damage" type="int"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the frame object"/>
    </request>

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="already_used" value="0" summary="the frame was already copied"/>
      <entry name="invalid_buffer" value="1" summary="buffer attributes are invalid"/>
    </enum>

    <enum name="flags">
      <entry name="y_invert" value="1" summary="the contents are y-inverted"/>
    </enum>
  </interface>
</protocol>

